[Applause]
here he comes ladies and Gentlemen
please welcome Stephanos
[Music]
[Applause]
Cass hello Yas did I say that
right yeah let's go with it welcome back
Melbourne you love this place don't you
last time you were here you met the guy
you're playing against tonight Novak
jovic was that the last time you played
him as well that's crazy cuz that's true
yeah in last time here has been with
Novak so how's it this time when you
come around playing him
different same exciting just different
setup we have some Greek traditional
dances here which is cool um I would
have never expected that uh Road labor
would get so festive and and so Lively
as now well we've got a big contingent
of Greek people here in Melbourne does
it feel like a home for you uh
absolutely I
mean I've I've played here since 2014
every single time that I come back I've
been greeted in the best possible way uh
Australia for me is home well that's it
well good luck tonight let's get ready
for the big
game stepanos has got plenty of support
here the Greek sensation back in
Victoria where they love him his
opponent though well over a decade or so
he's managed to make Rod laa Arena his
house and tonight the 10 time champ
returns
[Music]
[Applause]
Novak jovic ascends the mountain and
reaches the
[Applause]
[Music]
summit
Majestic again
[Music]
[Applause]
ladies and gentlemen the world number
one and 24 time Grand Slam Champion
Novak jovic
[Music]
[Applause]
Novak what a walk out song hi now 10
time Champion when you're walking
through that Hall of Champions does it
feel real is it ever going to feel
real um yeah I have to pinch myself
honestly after so many years of uh
professional tennis uh coming back to
Road labor arena is always extra special
so I don't take these evenings for
granted especially tonight it's very
special evening and I want to thank
tennis Australia um obviously this is
all part of a the week prior to the
Australian Open that um you know all the
proceeds go to Australian Open
foundation and I'm really grateful to to
stepanos uh for joining um and all you
who have bought tickets to come out and
and support a great course and hopefully
you'll have a great time tonight now
it's not just tennis you're playing here
tonight we've got some gymnastics we got
some basketball Cricket I didn't even
know you knew what cricket was but which
one are you most looking forward to
tonight oh I'm looking forward to
every bit of the program that we have I
don't know how much am I supposed to
talk about it or reveal what's secret
what's not but uh we're going to have a
lot of fun obviously tennis um being the
Central Point uh but at the same same
time we're going to have some special
guests from champions of their
respective Sports uh people that are
very well known in Australia and
worldwide and we're going to try our
luck playing different sports um and
also you know I'm not supposed to say
too much but anyway we're going to have
a great evening and I want to thank
everyone for coming out really made this
evening special thank you so much well
good luck tennis first
always no that jovic they love him here
are you ready for this
Melbourne I most certainly are a special
night ahead it's a night with no back
and friends but don't expect it to be
too friendly when these two hit the
court coming up jovic V sitz pass at a
rocking R La Arena
[Music]
[Applause]
all right so we got Peta and we've got
uh Felix with us good thank you
what's your
name all right guys so we'll just face
this way all uh just a few reminders for
us uh no lets no ad scoring uh you guys
are basically running the house ped and
Felix are going to do the coin TOS no
lets so you just like play we play what
do you mean we play with let you play on
let you play on oh
wow all right let's do the coin toss
first and then we'll take a photo so can
you please show Stephanos both size of
the coin want
or anything
one what would you like another okay
I'll Pi that he
I okay
yep I was dreaming time ago the coin
toss and Peter magic was out there
tonight loves his tennis just like his
brother Marco who was treated for neuro
Blasta his family needing to travel to
and from the United States for treatment
and a reminder you can help through the
Australian tennis Foundation tonight
brighter Futures is what they support
through tennis o
open.com ADF all for a great cause
tonight proceeds heading that way and
great to have little Peter out here
tonight supporting it as well Andy's
family so let's get on with the tennis
and head of the commentary box it's a
very good evening Casey DEA and Todd
Woodbridge well thank you very much
James good evening everybody and uh what
a trait what a special occasion to be
able to have um a match like this
between the world number one and
Stephanos to pass a final from a year
ago Casey um the atmosphere it's it's
it's party like when the Australian Open
always has that type of feel but this is
even more relaxed we get to see these
guys playing in an environment where we
can see a little bit more of their
personality it's pretty special isn't it
Todd it was electric out there all the
pre match LED lights going off and as
you said to be have the luxury to watch
these two Champions play out here and
they play obviously in the final last
year but what a special opening week and
as you said what I love about this is
that we get to see a little bit more of
their personalities and we get to see
that in a more relaxed environment which
is something pretty special that tennis
certainly needs and talking you use the
word relaxed I mean there's no more
relaxed than um our Courtside
commentator here tonight good evening
John Fitzgerald how are you
Fitzy well he's got to get his mic up
and running he's not he's not there yet
I know he's talking into it we we'll
switch him on in a moment but while we
wait for him to get to get that working
we'll take a look at Novak jovic of
course he's the world number one 98
career titles to his name at the moment
and
uh Sports Science Serbian scientists
named a species of beetle after him did
you know that I did not know that but
I've learned something new about Novak
jovic that's a very different looking
relaxed just like the
environment well one thing we know about
him is that he's got his own Foundation
he gives a lot he he likes to be out and
about in public and he's certainly got a
personality there's no doubt about that
he's not he's not short of personalities
no and that's why we love him not only
because he's won 24 Grand Slam titles 10
Australian opens but the fact that he
does give so much back to the sport he's
going to have a huge Legacy and and how
fortunate we are to have been witness to
his career what he's actually achieved
is just phenomenal and the type of
athlete he is is
extraordinary he's taking on the wall
number three tonight stepanos City bass
of course the runner up here last year
he's got 10 ATP titles to his name
that's good that's good but when he
plays someone with 98 that's heading
towards 100 it's just got the most
extraordinary record it's it's a tough
ask but you know what when you're in a
position like Steph is this is relaxed
but you get a good feel about where your
game is and actually you might be able
to try a few things and tactically you
might be less likely to in a fullon
match situation and I wonder whether
we'll see him do that tonight because
they're head-to-head Casey it's a little
bit rough for uh stepanos it's 112 in
favor of Novak and Steph won two out of
the first three encounters back in 2018
he won the first one then it went one
all then Steph won the next one in 2019
in Shanghai and then it's been oneway
traffic yeah and the closest I think
they had a five Setter back in
2021 they had a five they had a five
Setter in Rolling garos in the final
when uh which was back in 2021 you're
right with that stely two sets to love
on that occasion and Novak May one of
his very famous recoveries that he's
been able to do on so many occasions
coming back from two sets to love in
five sets he's the hardest man to beat
ever over a five set
competition as you said other than that
it's pretty much been oneway traffic for
Novak against C pass and yeah I think
this is what a what a great chance to
play in front of this many people on the
court surface on the court on Rod lab
Arena prior to the event and yeah it be
good to see steps so volley come forward
maybe mix in a few different things so
see what we're in for
for noage
[Applause]
to oh what a way to start maybe a few
Aces this will be a one set competition
no add scoring so if it gets to juice it
will be the returners decision of what
side they'd like to take that
pretty blustery conditions um this
afternoon in Melbourne particularly on
the outside courts here at Melbourne
Park where we've got the qualifying
event well and truly underway good
crowds around the grounds here 24 that's
the number of slams that he has
obviously going for number 25 and had so
much success here in
Australia just see there he just moves
so effortlessly just great footwork
around the ball looking for a forehand
4050 Todd I think you can hear me now
and the it is a tiny bit Gusty tiny bit
a little bit from the Northern end
behind Novak's
[Applause]
back first game nice little e easy
service game for Novak just to he's on
into what you'd call like part of the
preparation for his defense of the
Australian Open title I think
Casey yeah we saw both these players
play in the united cup moak won his
singles matches obviously going down to
Alex demor
Steph had a win there and also one loss
as well so but a match like this and out
out on court as step walks around there
in the crowd Australian cricket Legend
Steve
Smith he'll be playing part Peter bow
there as well he's going to be one of
the special guests with Novak later in
our coverage along with Georgia Godwin
and Alan
Williams pass
to so our first look at Steph both these
guys played the United cup in the
opening week of the season of course the
season starting still in
[Music]
[Applause]
2023 L has been a a conversation a lot
of us have had a where where is the
growth for Novak because I feel like
there is just everything he does he does
so well
and it's so hard to break his game down
[Music]
Todd well yeah there are no weaknesses
but but what he continues to do is to
improve them the the the Lesser parts of
his game so as an example now he wins
the US Open last year and puts on a
display of surving in the final which he
doesn't normally use his tactics in his
game and you go where have you been
hiding that because it was
extraordinarily
good and so let's go 10 years back into
his career that wasn't something that he
would have been able to implement in a
final like he did and it was a bit of
Tactical
Brilliance you know the little 1% as you
talk about you think about no all the
little bits that he does to get well was
here at the Australian
Open kind of about 09 10 and he would
struggle in the heat get him on a very
hot day in the afternoon here and he'd
almost Keel over and so he went
searching for why is this happening to
me if it's not hot I'm okay and he went
deep into the diet and that's where he
became based yeah glutenfree and worked
out okay my body doesn't react to
certain foods I eat particularly well I
get away with it but when I get exposure
to heat that's something I can improve
bang he improveed that doesn't struggle
in those conditions anymore
beautifully play there by S pass but
you're right it absolutely is the
1centers 4050
Fitzy yeah I'm a little worried I don't
want to put a dampener on this but I
Stefanos had some issues with his back
in Sydney last week I'm I'm a tiny bit
worried about it here in the second game
just a little
ginger he he yeah he looks like he's got
some pain to me
6y
pass one game over
well we'll take a look at that service
action of sit pass big wide base on
serve so he's going to have to really uh
push up through there the one thing that
he does do is he has a little awkward
landing and the way he lands Fitzy I
don't think puts it it would actually
put a little bit extra stress on the
back I believe yeah and he he was
looking at his uh his bench too with a
with a really worried look on his face
after the first game
let's hope it's just uh warming
up L
15 there is team s the pass
they're a fun
team United Cup last week team Greece
always full of
laughter always having good time visit T
visited tangazo and some wonderful
pictures from there
dad on your left of screen there postos
[Applause]
much being an elite athlete we talk
about the one centers with Novak and and
getting every inch out of his body his
mind and everything that he does staying
fit is so crucial isn't it in becoming
becoming not only a successful player
but having longevity on the tour yeah
fit fit and flexible and one of the
things that we know so much about jovic
is that when he's pushed out into the
the extreme corners of the Court he has
this ridiculous flexibility that sees
him able to get down so low and then
rebound back into the center of the
Court get himself into that neutral
position nobody's the style of movement
that he has
no to get it enrange the way he does we
see it so often and then to also recover
and get back into the the middle part of
the
Court there something that Novak does
better than
most well then we're on ser been this
friendly here on Rod La Arena tonight
with Novak and he's got the lead 2-1 in
the opening set it's two games to
one nice little start back looking nice
and relaxed it what we see here is that
very different intensity to what you
would see from him when he's in in that
match scenario and it's kind of nice to
kind of break in there I guess we might
hear from him in a moment or
two but um yeah
he's pondering a little isn't he he may
not be in pain a little bit stiff
working his way through just see him
even working the stomach muscles and the
lower back there just trying to work
things out
Todd the word
it this is a night with Novak and
friends and what a night we are having
here already a great bars Rod La Arena
tonight now host is the world number one
and 24 time Grand Slam Champion Noak the
arm there's been a lot of talk about it
mate how is it holding up tonight so far
good thank you thanks for asking has got
to check in on your health particularly
when you're chasing an 11th a strain
open title now over the other side of
the Court there's a little Dugout over
there with all the sports stars you're
going to be going up against later
tonight they're from uh sports stars
from right around Australia there's one
called Steve Smith he's front and center
over there with his beautiful wife Danny
and Steve is known for a bit of Shadow
batting he's a cricketer and that he
does he practices I saw him because he
knows he's going to play tennis before
practicing his swing I think he's ready
for a bit of a challenge from you later
on
mate uh well it's a great pleasure to
have Mr Smith and everyone else who is
uh out here with us tonight um I'm
really looking forward to try their
respective Sports I did play cricket in
Perth last week uh on the beach uh so I
don't know if you can count that really
as a real Cricket but um I I hit couple
of Sixers you know uh couple of fours so
uh and I had uh many missed balls as
well so uh I guess um you know heading
heading uh heading up against him will
be tough you got the go down pat we'll
let you get back out there and do what
you do best Novak jovic ladies and
gentlemen our host Tonight look out for
it Steve Smith Novak jovic that's not
too far away but right now stepanos pass
is his main
[Applause]
[Music]
target Stephanos pass coming out fit he
did look a little bit Ginger was having
a chat there to one of the officials but
uh he just needs to cruise on along here
doesn't need to do too much no need to
push himself but still needs to feel
what it's like out on court still plenty
of time ahead before the draw
starts yeah Todd I I agree he doesn't
need to push himself 100% it's it's a
little lighthearted they they'll play
well if they can but he is ginger let me
tell
you well the back's been I think a bit
of an issue for a while now and he did
play a little bit of tennis at the
United cup but
L 15
we took a bit of pace off that serve
there
170 came around the outside of the ball
DED to get a little bit more Spin and
movement
[Music]
[Applause]
great Court coverage here from both
players
this one trying to get it down at the
toes so sits pass has to heat up tried a
little bit of tried to put him off a
little bit with no luck popped it right
over the head
[Applause]
little rare error off the forehand don't
see Miss hit too many just catches that
one early in the top of the frame have a
look at that early evening just on 7:00
now here in Melbourne and a full
house for a night with
Novak there usually is a few nights with
Novak here at the Australian Open but
this one a little more relaxed and extra
special well that brings up break point
but you're right Todd the atmosphere
coming in tonight was was pretty special
actually felt
like a night with Nova
exciting remind them they can get loud
they can be a little they don't have to
follow the full tennis etiquette
tonight interesting with s a pass cuz in
his bio he said his surface is grass he
shot is forehand and tournament is
Wimbledon which as I think that would
have been put in the bio a number of
years ago and as his career has
progressed that's been his least best
surface and worst performing
tournament he's been better on clay and
hardcore with shots like that that
forehand on
song and Fitzy foran looks good yeah
foran's always looking good one of the
best in the game he told me today I had
a chat with him today he told me that it
was hardc and Clay so what I I'm reading
his ATP bio and yeah learned a lot of
his tennis on Clay as a youngster and
has evolved onto hardcore likes them
both
they need to update the bio perhaps but
if you're wondering why it's to all
because we did have a juice
point there is a a champion of the game
Goran Evanovich working as coach now as
for no doovic
[Applause]
not a bad idea tough to hit a Top Spin
lob with a one-handed backand like that
you struggle to get enough racket head
speed from that Wing much easier to flip
one over with a two-handed back hand
15 he plays the back spinner look at
that that's where you impart the spin
cups the racket behind the ball watch
the ball bounce here it'll stop go
backwards thir
[Applause]
403 now there's a Ser volley that we
talked about the a classic move and
jovic got all the classics hasn't he
he's G 32 here in this first set on
[Music]
we are Byers aliot who else is joining
us hang
on
WE
is
triy how do you think you're playing
well I think we are playing unbelievably
well we
[Applause]
and he certainly got plenty here tonight
at packed house at Rod La Arena he's
having a bit of fun courtside at the
moment the news to hand is Def s passes
headed off for a bit of physio work now
we do know that throughout his United
cup campaign he had a stiff at
withdrawal from a match it was giving
him some grief there and clearly he's
looking a little tight tonight so the
Greek Superstars just headed off Court
uh for a bit of work and West standing
by to see just how fit he is to continue
this match up tonight uh against Novak
jovic a bit of fun being had court side
here the crowd this is what happens uh
when things slow down and a player
leaves the court and the contest has to
stop for just the
moment impersonators next thing know
we'll have clowns out here doing a bit
of juggling and why
not uh but we're Courtside right now
ladies and gentlemen uh Rod lab arena
for those uh wondering where Stephanos
has gone he's just getting a bit of
physio work behind the scenes his back
has been giving a bit of grief of late
great to have everyone's company joining
us right around the world tonight as
well Georgie and I are going to head
over to where the stars are sitting
that'll be out on court a little later
tonight Steve could you come on out mate
great to see you ladies and gentlemen
Steve
Smith good to see you mate uh
congratulations the promotion to the top
of the order ready against the West
Indies next week well done mate thank
you mate it should be good fun uh did I
actually see you Shadow racket swinging
before was I right oh you might have so
you're going to challenge him Le show
know back how to do Cricket later on
tonight but there's also going to be a
bit of tennis against the man
himself intimidated of course yeah he's
the best isn't he so um now looking
forward to hitting a few balls it should
be good fun what's it like sitting
Courtside in an arena like this I mean
you've walked out in front of huge
crowds at a G right around the world but
this place it's something special isn't
it yeah it is and I've been lucky to
come down here a few on a few occasions
and I've actually seen no back play here
so um you know he's great to watch they
move so gracefully around the court and
you see the ball flying at good pace so
it's um yeah it's great fun to watch
they do sport pretty well and they do a
crowd well in this part of the world
don't they what about Melbourne turning
out tonight in the stral up it hasn't
even started yet yeah it's impressive
isn't it um you know it's a great
Precinct down here um like I said I've
been down a few times it's I love coming
down here and watching some tennis and
and watching the stars go about their
business West Indies two tests uh great
form against Pakistan from the entire
Australian team you guys feeling well
placed yeah we've we've been playing
well the last couple of years so um yeah
two more tests for the summer West
Indies um I don't know a lot of the
players they brought out so a few new
ones but um I'm I'm sure they'll be
competitive and yeah looking forward to
it mate looking forward to seeing you
get amongst the runs and Notch a couple
of Victories for Australia again well
done ladies and gentlemen Steve Smith
joining his Courtside here he's going to
be out on the court a little later on
can't wait for that uh Georgie you're
with another special guest tonight oh
Superstars Galore here and what a view
this is how good being at at Melbourne
here for the tenant oh man it's unreal
it's one of my favorite probably event
in Australia so it's good to be here and
good to see the crowd to up you've been
a big joic fan for a while yeah massive
fan and um I have to go against him
later so that's a bit bit tough now the
other day was 200 days to the Paris
Olympics it's been a big three years
really since the last Olympics the last
six months what's it going to look like
for you a a lot of running a lot of
training and just just trying to be
mentally there and getting through each
day consistency ski leading up to
Olympics and I mean we're fourth last
Olympics and we're just going to try to
do better no are as well thank you good
luck against Novak later on thank you
very much
apprciate great to see Peter bowan out
out Superstar here tonight another one
of our big Aussie athletes that'll be
out on court very soon sideline
Courtside with uh with Novak now you're
working up a sweat out here and
Stephanos is back out in the court
ladies and gentlemen good to see Steph
come on in come on in B the other half
of this show tonight uh how are you
feeling mate I know you got a little bit
of work done behind the scenes are you
feeling okay I'm feeling okay I just
decided to take a dollar break all right
you want to go back out play some tennis
I'm kind of popular for that so I
decided all right you too get back out
there let's get it on ladies and
gentlemen give him a round of applause
no back Stephanos ready to go
[Applause]
again little tongue and cheek there from
Stephano B he says I'm known for a
little bit of a toilet break thank you
have been having a little bit of
physiotherapy just quickly there just
trying to loosen things up but good news
he's back out on court he's serving
trailing 23 on serve in this
set that's why we have Fitzy court side
he doesn't miss a beat does he Fitzy he
knows what's going
on he's serving about 3/4 Pace at the
moment so I can relate to that speed
yeah I was going to say what what's that
compared to yours fits what about your
bomb
175 people living in Glass Houses Todd
don't don't throw So Many Stones Hey
listen I I always throw my mix doubles
Partners they had to serve bigger than
me and ask Alicia moik she'll tell you
that's the truth I'm sure she did
[Music]
[Applause]
you know what's interesting FY when you
watch a a match like this when you can
see they're just like for Novak in
particular you actually see his level so
he's hitting the ball beautifully here
and he would be trying a shot like that
very rarely in a match but you get to
see him do something a little
different he's so disciplined that we
often don't see the creative side of him
well you'd see that in a practice match
where like when he's warming up the week
before and playing practice sets with
players you'd see it more than wouldn't
you and it's a bit like that tonight
really is an amazing crowd here though
Todd J it's it's if there's 15,000
packed here there must be 148 I
reckon 14 13
site looking
amazing if you are coming over the next
couple of weeks I can assure you the
site is
ready looks amazing plenty of spaces
plenty of
shade and plenty of great
tennis yes deciding Point receiver
Choice another deciding Point very we
rarely see this format where it gets to
juice we see this in doubles where it's
a juice Point deciding Point wins and
the receiver will get to choose which
side they like to receive from
oh and there is the break forand
slightly Miss hit push wide by sitas and
jovic as the break for games the
two when you're not moving at your
absolute best that's when you see those
little bit of mish hits like that one
there not quite adjusting the feet as
well as he would have liked there sit a
pass timing not as clean and crisp as
you would be used to
see 15 long and F really struggling off
the slice backand
tonight well I think it's just what you
said he he's his movement is is not 100%
so he's just slightly out of position a
lot of the time and then it's hard to
hit the ball in the middle every
[Applause]
time 3
left little sneaky 199 km an hour out
wide from no
back you can see the difference with
Novak those small adjustment steps
around the ball always in fantastic
position both of these players are such
good ball Strikers but no
just his ability to find
Space you see here good pitcher just
small adjustment steps before he
unleashes back in
crosscourt oh that one catches the line
as well some clean hitting from jovic
however good signs for him and his fans
he's got 5-2 in this
set jovic leads five games the two
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah some slowmo there there a couple of
balls off the sitsu past ret where he
just he's not quite centering it that
well is
he he's certainly
not and it gets Amplified if you like
when you're playing against Novak
absolutely if you're not in that ideal
and perfect
position there someone that's going to
expose your movement or your ability to
hit clean off the racket it's
Novak and wow Noak is looking
sharp how are you enjoy thech tonight
enjo very
so here we are night with Novak and uh
this a replay if you like of the final
from here last year Novak jovic winning
that one in straight sets and he's got
an early break here in this set at 52
against Stephanos SASS and of course
Novak started his campaign for 2024 in
the united Cup in Perth where uh he had
a win and a loss lost Australia's Alex
demono a little bit of trouble with his
right wrist and forearm but there looks
like there is none of that out here
tonight hasn't touched it gone near it
ball striking has been good and you know
the one thing we know about him Casey is
that his preparation and the Perfection
that he puts into that to be ready to go
five sets over two weeks is Flawless and
he's looking very good
here he is the ultimate professional and
I'm not sure there's I mean over the
length of five set tennis Todd there's
not many that play five set tennis
better than Noak jovic in terms of
managing each
set well there's a number of players out
on tour fit I think that can play the
level required 3 to push Novak but he
can his levels he stays at them for
longer than just about anybody that's
ever played the game would that be fair
that's some it up for me Todd
exactly he doesn't drop off it's a rare
thing when he drops off and and that's a
hard thing as a as a pro you know to
maintain that level constantly
particularly against his
[Applause]
standard 4
left you see it often in matches really
good players who will put everything
into a first set for instance they might
win that in a close one or even lose it
but but then they've got to start again
immediately he he's the best at doing
that oh swinging Drive Vol from
sit and a nice little hold to love keeps
himself in it jovic leads five games to
three
50 l
[Applause]
fifth in O and that was beautiful up
onto that short one got jovic at full
stretch and then drops a racket whips it
here look to the racket head speed bang
wonderful execution from Cy
pass third
50 jovic's placement on that out wide
serve on the juice court is just
impeccable he gets it short in the box
that one hitting the line and taking
off it's been some pretty good spots
iring as we like to
say accuracy and speed into the corner
sets up a nice little putaway like that
and
here we are at two match points two set
points in this
encounter and he starts it as he
finished it Noak jovic that's with an
Ace and the friendly against C passes
six games to
three we're far from done here a night
with Novak and Friends a 63 win for
Novak over his good mate and last year's
finalist with him Stephan